This is the BBC.
This podcast is supported by advertising outside the UK.
From global current affairs to art, science and culture.
The documentary from the BBC World Service tells the world's stories.
Search for The Documentary wherever you get your BBC podcasts.
Hello and welcome to More or Less on the BBC World Service.
We're your weekly guide to the numbers in the news and in life.
I'm Charlotte McDonald.
Tonight at ten, the FBI has arrested a suspect in the worst leak of secret US intelligence documents in years.
We're going live to the Pentagon.
That's where the spokesman, Patrick Ryder, is taking questions and speaking right now on the origins of leaked documents that have been made public.
Under arrest, a member of the Air National Guard suspected in the unprecedented leak of America's secrets.
The leaking of US intelligence documents and the arrest of a 21-year-old airman who authorities believe to be responsible has caused a media and diplomatic storm.
Many of the documents, some of which are marked top secret, paint a detailed picture of the war in Ukraine.
The leaks have been widely reported, including by US channel Fox News, many of whose hosts have been critical of the American government's policy in Ukraine.
This is what Fox News primetime host Tucker Carlson had to say about what the leak showed.
The second thing we learn from these slides is that despite direct US involvement, Ukraine is in fact losing the war.
Seven Ukrainians are being killed for every Russian. Ukrainian air defences have been utterly degraded. Ukraine is losing.
So, according to Tucker Carlson, the leaked presentation slides show seven Ukrainians are being killed for every one Russian, which would be a pretty shocking finding.
If those figures were true, then it'd be pretty catastrophic for the Ukrainians because I'm not like a war expert, but when you defend your own land, you usually give a lot more casualties out than you take.
Eric Toler has been working on the leaked document story. He's director of research and training for Bellingcat, an investigative journalism site that specialises in using open source intelligence.
It's played a leading role in tracing the spread of the leaked documents on social media platforms like Discord and Telegram.
The first job was to work out whether they really were US intelligence documents. They seemed legitimate, but there was one that appeared to have been altered.
It was just one single document that was modified very crudely and it's very obvious that it was fake.
The fake document was the one that discussed Russian and Ukrainian casualties.
There was one single file that was modified related to casualty figures of the Ukrainian and Russian militaries.
This was modified over a month after the file was initially released on Discord and it was just some Telegram channel, not like a Russian government source.
So this could be as simple as one pro-Russian user very crudely photoshopping one section of one image to make Ukraine look worse and Russia look better.
The numbers are off-centre, they're not quite spaced correctly and it's just kind of crude. It's as if I did it.
So on the original undoctored image, the number of Russian troops killed is more than double the number of Ukrainian soldiers killed.
But on the crudely doctored slide, the Russian losses have been reduced and the Ukrainian troop deaths have been vastly increased.
So all of a sudden Ukraine has a lot more deaths.
But despite Tucker Carlson saying the slides contain evidence of a seven to one kill rate, even the doctored figures don't show that.
We tried to get Fox News to give us any more information about this claim, but we received no response.
Eric believes it doesn't matter whether the mistake was made by Carlson or his producer, such an error should have been avoided.
If you're a producer on a TV show, you should theoretically be able to fact check the stuff that you're citing in your report, but some people are better about it than others, to put it politely.
Even if we can completely dismiss Tucker Carlson's claim about the casualty numbers in these leaked documents, how reliable are the numbers that US intelligence are quoting?
The BBC's Russian service has been compiling a list of Russian service personnel killed in the conflict.
Senior correspondent Olga Ivshena says the US estimate of Russians killed in action, up to 43,500, seems to tally with their own work.
She explained how they calculate their figures.
Our primary goal is to count all the Russian losses, so Russian personnel killed in action.
And we do so by gathering all the publicly valuable information.
So first of all, it's different media reports from different outlets in Russia, heads of local schools, heads of local libraries, heads of villages, tiny regional newspapers.
On top of that, we monitor Russian social media and when relatives of a certain person who died during the invasion.
And another very important source of information are different memorials, monuments and graveyards.
So we have an opportunity to monitor situation in over 60 cemeteries all over Russia.
So compiling that all together, we currently have a database of 21,000 Russian servicemen who were killed during the invasion.
As we monitor situation on the cemeteries, we see that each time we get access there, we see all the names which were mentioned in the public domain.
And on top of that, usually the similar amount of names which clearly died during the invasion, but they weren't mentioned publicly.
Based on that, we think that our database has 50% less names than the real number of Russian military casualties figure which were buried in Russia.
So if currently we have names of 21,000 Russian soldiers killed in action, our assessment is that total number of Russian casualties, so killed only, must be around 42,000.
Fox News itself has been in the headlines in the last few days.
It was due to defend itself in a giant defamation case brought by Dominion Voting Systems,
who alleged that Fox aired false claims that Dominion's voting machines helped steal the election from Donald Trump.
The case was settled at the last minute, but the day before it was due to start, Fox News took out a full-page ad in the New York Times with the headline,
"Trusted now more than ever."
It then goes on to list what it says are the TV network's most trusted for news.
Fox News itself is at the top of the bar chart with 41%, trailed by ABC News on 24%, CNN and CBS on 22%, NBC on 21% and MSNBC on 18%.
So you might think that's pretty clear.
If you ask Americans which news channel they trust the most, the answer is Fox News.
But actually, that is the opposite of what you find, according to Elliot Morris, a senior data journalist for The Economist.
If you just ask Americans which news network do you trust the most, then Fox News actually scores very poorly.
Whereas things like the BBC, ABC, CNN have about 40% of Americans saying those sources are very trustworthy or somewhat trustworthy,
Fox News scores closer to 30% and they have a lot more Americans saying they're untrustworthy than those mainstream news sources.
So the reality seems to be pretty significantly different than the advertisement they took out.
So how does the advertisement suggest something so different? Well, look at the small print.
It seems what Fox News has done is not ask one question, but two questions.
Which of the following networks do you watch? And then they've listed all of the major news networks, so Fox, ABC, CNN, right, a couple of others.
And then, well, they don't tell us how they did this, but my read of them asking the second question is among people who said they watched Fox News,
they then asked which news network do you trust the most.
And of course, if you watch Fox News, it's one of the only pretty mainstream right-leaning news networks in America.
You probably don't trust the other news networks, which you think are too centrist or left-leaning.
So, Elliott's take on the advert is, it shows Fox News is the kind of news channel that attracts an audience that agrees with its political outlook and trusts it.
It's the most trusted channel by its audience, but one of the least trusted by the general population.
We asked Fox News about the advert. They told us that the data is from YouGov.
We approached the polling company who say the data used is for media companies to learn more about their audiences only.
And these are not the results of any recent nationally representative survey.
That's it for this edition of More or Less. We'll be back next week.
If you want to get in contact, you can email us at moreorless@bbc.co.uk.
But for now, goodbye.
Exploring the events shaping our lives through original documentary storytelling.
We'll hear arguments in a row against Wade.
The documentary from the BBC World Service is a window onto the wider world.
The security situation in Europe has changed in the last couple of years dramatically.
Search for The Documentary wherever you get your BBC podcasts.